# JEFFREY BOX

#### Atlanta, GA | (404) 488-9350 | JeffreyLBox@gmail.com | jeffreybox.github.io →



# **STATEMENT**

Healthcare Data Scientist with eight years of experience and an education background including: BS ISYE, MBA, MHA, and CPPS and Data Science certifications. Successful career contributions are rooted in translating raw data into meaningful action for improvement. This value is created by leading teams and projects, conducting focus groups, and performing effective senior-level presentations. Strengths and passions include procedural thinking, tool creation and automation, programming, creative thinking, deep work, and unique problem-solving. Passion for knowing work is making an impact by improving quality and safety and reducing harm across the care-continuum.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib), SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS | Reporting & Visualization: Advanced Excel & VBA, Tableau, D3, Leaflet, Plotly, R | Database: Oracle, Postgres, Mongo, SQLAlchemy, Access, Business Objects | Other: Git, Flask, Heroku, Beautiful Soup (BS4), APIs (JSON, GeoJSON) | Machine Learning: Hadoop, SciKit Learn, & Tensor Flow | Statistics: Modelling, Forecasting, DOE, Munging

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Beterra Health, Inc.

Senior Improvement Leader: Newnan and Atlanta, GA (2016 - 2018)

- Summary: Helped develop this spin-off startup on the initial team by leading the consulting and analytics practices. This was done by delivering value to clients at the executive level, assist and support engineering in product develop, and help create innovative content for healthcare improvement around the world. Additionally, supported sales efforts as a Patient Safety/Quality subject matter expert.
- Projects: Managed Safety Culture projects, analysis of AHRQ data, onsite delivery, and relationships for over 200 various acute care, long-term, and clinic-based clients across the US including: University Hospital of Pennsylvania System, Eastern Maine Health System, Inova Health System, Abington-Jefferson Health, Florida Hospital Association (FHA), Missouri Hospital Association (MHA), Mercy Health (St. Louis), Virtua Health, and Meadows Regional in Augusta, GA. Developed in house tools for mining, munging, and sense-making

# Synensys Health, LLC

Lead Analytics Consultant: Peachtree City, GA and Doha, Qatar (2013 – 2016)

- Summary: Led an analytics team of five in Healthcare improvement projects by creating systematic processes and tools for
  tracking safety analytics. This primarily focused on Safety Culture AHRQ data analysis, TeamSTEPPS® implementations, High
  Reliability (HRO) and Just Culture projects, and Human Factors analyses. Other analyses included correlation with patient
  satisfaction (HCAHPS), quality (P4P Quality Indicators), and ACA "Pay for Performance" Value Based Purchasing (VBP) metrics,
  focus groups, interviews, on-site assessments, and Kirkpatrick® and InsideOut® coaching training and measurement.
- Projects: Led projects on the Air Force Medical Service Patient Safety Program (PSP) government contract to improve patient
  safety across 32 Military Treatment Facilities (MTFs) worldwide. Hospital and health system work included: North Carolina and
  Virginia (NoCVA) group, Hugh Chatham Memorial Hospital, UC Irvine, and Middle East clients such as Corniche and King Faisal
  Security Hospital, Sheridan Memorial Hospital in Wyoming and Virtua Health in New Jersey.

# **Northside Hospital**

Application Analyst: Atlanta, GA (2011 - 2013)

- Summary: Worked in Information Systems with the McKesson-based internal clinical applications (Horizon Clinicals) for the all campuses. This included working with clinical staff and assisting with organization-wide upgrades and go-lives.
- Projects: Managed and improved existing SQL reports, wrote new reports, and migrated reports as needed. Additionally, managed various TTY systems in the hospitals UNIX and supported internal projects for all campuses.

# **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

- Georgia State University: Master of Health Administration (MHA) 2014
- Georgia State University: Master of Business Administration (MBA) 2014
- Georgia Institute of Technology: Bachelor of Science (BS) Industrial and Systems Engineering (ISYE) 2008
- Georgia Institute of Technology: Certificate of Program Completion in Data Science and Analytics (GTPE) 2018
- National Patient Safety Foundation (NPSF): Certification in Professional Patient Safety (CPPS) 2017